# **AKSHAY G**

# Front-End Developer | JavaScript | React | Html | Css

+91 **87 54 070533 akshayg2422**@gmail.com **Gummidipoondi**, Chennai

#### **SUMMARY**

Persevering learner and diligent team player with 2 years of experience specialising in UI development using the React library. Skilled software engineer with expertise in AI-powered recruiting applications, HRMS, ticket management, educational timeline systems, and ERP applications. You can view my portfolio here.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### INTRVU SPACE — Hiring Application (AI)

### https://www.intrvu.space/

• intrvu SPACE helps you conduct automated Interviews, Generate Reports, and Approve Candidates end to end with zero manual effort.

**Contribution:** Landing page, Login, OTP, Corporate flow, CRUD candidate flow, Settings, Job seeker flow, Report

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

### Zeny Q — HRMS

# https://www.zenuq.com/

• Employee management application with features like attendance and payroll management.

**Contribution:** Api integration and data normalisation, Salary slip.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, push notification

### Quanta TMS — Ticket Management Solution

# https://www.quantatms.in/

• Enhances task and ticket management for improved collaboration.

**Contribution:** Login, OTP, Individual chats, Group chats, Task, Ticket, Association, Feeds, Events

**Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

# Quanta EDAT — EduTech Application

### https://www.quantaedat.com/

• Offers comprehensive programming courses with practical tasks and mock interviews.

**Contribution:** Course CRUD, Tasks, Topics, Schedule Interview, Online Sessions **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

#### NS Instruments - FG — Finished Goods Management

• Optimises inventory control with streamlined stock and product management.

**Contribution:** Login, OTP, Dispatch request, Stock request and Paginated Listing **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

#### **EXPERIENCE**

React JS Developer - 06/2022 - Present

Leora Infotech Private Limited - Gummidipoondi, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design and development
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

### **Tele Marketing Assistant** - 17/03/2022 - 31/05/2022

Malayala Manorama Company Limited - Egmore, Chennai.

- As a Payment Assistant, I facilitated payments and supported users navigating the payment page.
- Utilizing chat and system calls, I addressed user concerns, convinced them of package benefits, and ensured a smooth transaction experience.

#### **Payment Assistance** - 30/09/2021 - 14/03/2022

MATRIMONY.COM LIMITED - Guindy, Chennai.

- As a Payment Assistant, I facilitated payments and supported users navigating the payment page.
- Utilizing chat and system calls, I addressed user concerns, convinced them of package benefits, and ensured a smooth transaction experience.

#### Data Provisioning Executive - 01/2019 - 11/2019

Tenth Planet Technologies - Mount Road, Chennai.

• Provide customised enterprise IT solutions, centred around open source software, troubleshoot issues, ensure compliance.

**Process Associate** - 04/2017 - 11/2017

String Information Services - Saidapet, Chennai.

• Mortgage Process Outsourcing (MPO) - tailored solutions, optimise and streamline mortgage processes, enhance efficiency, reduce costs.

### **SKILLS**

<u>Javascript</u>, <u>Typescript</u>, <u>HTML</u>, <u>CSS</u>, <u>React</u>, <u>Bootstrap</u>, <u>Redux</u>, <u>Redux Saga</u>, <u>React Router</u>, <u>Git</u>, <u>GitHub</u>, <u>Bit bucket</u>, <u>Rest</u>, <u>Axios</u>, <u>Fetch</u>, <u>Scss</u>, <u>Firebase</u>, <u>i18n-js</u>, <u>Jitsi</u>, <u>validate.js</u>, React-player, React-photo-view, React-DND, React-Select

### **EDUCATION**

Bsc Computer Science - 2013 - 2016 Shree Chandraprabhu Jain College Minjur, Chennai.

XII (HSS) - 2011 -2013 St.Marys Matric Hr Sec Chinthala Kuppam, Gummidipoondi.

X (SSLC) - 2010 - 2011 Shanthiniketan Matric Hr Sec New Gummidipoondi.

# **LANGUAGES**

**Tamil:** Mother Tongue **English:** Professional (Conversationally fluent)

Malayalam: Conversationally fluent Hindi: Writing and Reading